# **DANIEL FUQUA | Software Engineer**

Telephone: (713)562-5966 Email: fuquardwork@gmail.com

Location: Nashville, TN

Github: <a href="https://github.com/DanielFuqua">https://github.com/DanielFuqua</a>
Portfolio: <a href="https://danielfuqua.com">https://danielfuqua.com</a>

## Summary

Full-stack Software Engineer with 1+ year experience in the design, installation, and maintenance of software systems. Equipped with a diverse and promising skill-set. Experienced with the latest cutting edge development tools and procedures. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team. I am a fast learner, enthusiastic, organized, and communicate well. Able to join teams and start delivering quickly.

## **Personal Projects**

MAY 2020

### Macro Manage

### https://github.com/DanielFuqua/Capstone

Macro-Manage is designed to help users catalog their favorite meals and control macro-nutrient intake. Macro Manage displays a list of foods stored by users with nutrient contents, and allows users to compile their favorite foods into meals that meet the user's desired macro intake.

Tools and Tech used: React, React Hooks, Reactstrap, Context API, JSON mock server

AUGUST 2020

#### Asana 26

#### https://github.com/DanielFuqua/Capstone-Full-Stack

A social app geared to help new yogis learn the 26 postures of Bikram (hot) yoga. Users can browse the different postures and get some instruction before ever walking into their first class, as well as connect with other yogis to ask questions and share their knowledge.

 Tools and Tech used: React, React Hooks, Reactstrap, React Router, Context API, C# / .NET Core, ASP.NET Core, SQL Server and Entity Framework

## **Experience**

#### **DECEMBER 2020 - PRESENT**

## **Labor Driven** – Software Developer (Remote)

- Collaborating with the founding team, dev team and design team to build the Labor Driven web application from the ground up
- Working with the engineering team to enhance performance and build new features for Labor driven web application
- Participating in weekly SCRUM meetings over Zoom to report progress on work that I am self-managing for the most part
- Tools & Technologies: React, Redux, React Hooks, CSS, Figma, etc

#### JUNE 2019 - JANUARY 2020

### **Uhaul Moving and Storage** - Sales & Customer Services

- Took inventory, stocked and maintained a quality, orderly and clean showroom
- Provided customers with quality assistance and information about products and procedures, with intention of selling them something they need
- Maintained an orderly schedule for trailer/truck/equipment rentals departures and returns / times and locations - via phone and in person
- Maintained quality trailers, trucks and other rental equipment kept clean and safe for use
- Coordinated congested parking lots with dozens of rental pick-ups and returns happening simultaneously and a store full of customers in need of assistance
- Secured safe trailers for customers picking up their equipment and unattached the returns quickly and safely
- Coordinated scheduling for trailer hitch installments between the customer and the in-store hitch expert

### Skills

#### **APRIL 2014 - PRESENT**

#### **Crypto Trader** – *Independent*

The Bitcoin white paper is what initially peaked my interest in software. And soon after Bitcoin solved the problem of centralized money systems using the blockchain architecture, Ethereum came along and showed how the same concepts could be used to handle all sorts of contractual agreements through the invention of smart-contracts. The implication of these technologies have inspired me to explore my potential as a software engineer and overall problem solver.

## **Education**

#### FEBRUARY 2020 - AUGUST 2020

#### Nashville Software School - Full-Stack Software Development

Intensive, hands-on 6 month full-stack software development program creating applications in team based environments and individually using modern technologies.

- Built single page applications with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap
- Learned functional React including hooks, styling with React Bootstrap
- Built databases use MySQL server
- Used C# / .NET to create backend APIs for full-stack application functionality
- Utilized Git and GitHub for version control and to facilitate collaboration when working remotely and on teams

## **Tech Stack**

Front-End: React, React Hooks, Redux, Sagas, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Styled-Components

Back-End: C#.Net, ASP.Net, Entity Framework

Databases: MySQL

Dabbled With: NodeJS, Gatsby, NextJS, Firebase, Stripe, Thunk Middleware